让我们使用前面的MATLAB示例来说明关于单应性的一些原则。第一
Let's use the previous MATLAB example to illustrate some principles around homographies. First
我要做的就是关闭这两个窗口并创建一个名为Little的新变量
thing I'm going to do is to close these 2 windows and create a new variable called Little
P，包含那些世界点的投影。开始了。
P, which contains the projection of those world points. Here we go.
因此，这是该摄像机所观察到的点的图像平面坐标
So, this is the image plane coordinates of the points as viewed by that camera up in
空气。世界点P是一组3维坐标。注意Z坐标
the air. The world points P are a set of 3 dimensional coordinates. Note that the Z coordinate
所有这些点都等于0.所以，我要创建一个新的向量，只有P和
of all of these points is equal to 0. So, I'm going to create a new vector, just P and
它只是前两行，它包含所有列。所以，这是Q.所以，Q是
it's just the first 2 rows and it contains all of the columns. So, this is Q. So, Q are
相机正在观察的地平面上的一组点坐标和P.
a set of coordinates of points on the ground plane that the camera is looking at and P
是一个像素坐标在视图中从那个相机在空中，现在
is a set of pixel coordinates in the view from that camera up in the air and now that
我有这两组相应的二维点，我可以计算单应性。我会用的
I have these 2 sets of corresponding 2-D points, I can compute an homography. I'll just use
单应性函数和我传递第一组点，小P和第二组
the homography function and I pass in the first set of points, little P and the second
点集，Q和这里是已经计算的单应矩阵。
set of points, Q and here is the homography matrix that's been computed.
现在我有单应性H，我可以将它应用于单个点或多个点。
Now that I have the homography H, I can apply it to a single point or to multiple points.
为了帮助我，有一个名为'homtrans'的工具箱辅助函数应用了
To help me with that, there is a toolbox helper function called 'homtrans' which applies the
单应性H到像素组P.这是我们的图像平面坐标和结果
homography H to the set of pixels P. This is our image plane coordinates and the result
是地面上点的坐标集。
is the set of coordinates of points on the ground.
我们已经在图像中映射了一组点，其坐标以单位为单位进行测量
We have mapped a set of points in the image whose coordinates are measured in units of
将像素分成地平面上的一组点，并描述其中的坐标
pixels into a set of points on the ground plane and there coordinates are described
以米为单位。同样地，我可以使用单应矩阵的逆来反过来。
in units of metres. Similarly, I can use the inverse of the homography matrix to go the other way.
所以现在，我传入地面上的点的坐标，结果是一组
So now, I pass in the coordinates of the points on the ground and the result is the set of
图像平面坐标。因此，如果我想映射，单应性是一个非常有用的工具
image plane coordinates. So, the homography is a really useful tool if I want to map the
一个平面与另一个平面之间的点坐标。
coordinates of points between one plane and another.